2550 Kingston rd Toronto, Ontario M1M 1L7 TEL: 6479135203

E-MAIL: tigerred25@yahoo.fr

Paul Asongwe Ngu

Profile

 A committed professional with a background in technical support (IT), administrative support, and customer service, proficient in both French and English. Drawing upon my extensive experience and skill set, I am confident in my ability to make a meaningful contribution towards the attainment of the business's objectives and goals if given the opportunity to contribute.

Work Experience

CIBC - Toronto, ON Bilingual QA mobile tester

Feb 2021 - Mar 2023

- Utilized JIRA platform for documenting and tracking various testing activities.
- Employed HPalm to validate the functionality of test scenarios on target devices.
- Leveraged CONFORMIQ to create testing stages and test diagrams for future reference.
- Deployed mobile applications on Jenkins for system testing on both native and web platforms, specifically for iPad and iPhone.
- Generated tickets to report and address glitches encountered during testing.
- Worked on resolving existing bugs that emerged after software updates.
- Edited mobile app pipeline codes using Groovy syntax for dummy testing and future mobile updates.
- Ensured smooth integration and functionality of the CIBC mobile app with upcoming iOS updates.

Salvation Army, ON Bilingual IT Technical support 2020

Mar 2020 - Nov

- I Provided technical assistance to employee while escalating urgent technical repairs to level two agents for rapid technical resolution.
- I Resolved employee concerns regarding their computers and windows setup devices through remote system (windows chat).
- In addition, I provided Hardware and software setup as well (Setting up vpn and security software programs for easy usage on employee computers and helping them understand the new types of software they will be using on-going).
- Security assistance and security advice was one of the services I provide to the employee to avoid spamming and phishing.
- I had to setup specific salvation army computers for their retail stores and shelter locations (new Microsoft 365 account setup for all communication and system activations)

 Created accounts and renewed accounts for new employee or exiting ones and terminated old accounts.

Scotia bank, ON Bilingual IT technical analyst May 2020

Oct 2017 -

- I Provided level 1 and 2 support to employee of the bank while escalating urgent technical repairs to level two agents for rapid technical resolution.
- Resolved employee concerns regarding their devices through remote system known as Bomgar.
- Hardware and software setup was a main routine for the bank (Setting up vpn and security software programs for easy usage on employee computers and helping them understand the new types of software they will be using on their various devices be it iOS, windows, or Rim).
- Security assistance and security advice was one of the services I provide to the employee.
- Remote education on the new software (Yolk) introduced by the bank was an assistance I provided as well to ease employees daily activities.
- I had to provide escalations to level two about critical situations that needed assistance to field technicians on more advance software maintenance support.

CIBC - Toronto, ON Bilingual Wealth Specialist

June 2015 - May 2017

- Assisted branch managers with bank updates and provided business relevant information.
- Resolved clients' concerns regarding RESP and TFSA accounts.
- Prepared appropriate tax slips for various branch managers creatin customer accounts.
- Helped branch managers with correct calculations for the clients' taxes (PERSONAL PORTFOLIO ACOUNTS, RESP, TFA).
- I had the Responsibility of providing up to date unlocking solutions to the various branches to assist clientele in withdrawing RESP or TFSA account savings.
- Ensured delivering up-to-date accurate information to clients with updated bank website links.

Global Payment Inc - Toronto, ON Bilingual Technical Support Agent

2014 - 2014 (contractor student)

- Answered calls from Merchants and Technicians.
- Worked with various computer applications to record, file, enter data.
- Troubleshot Point of Sale terminals.
- Setup new terminals over the phone with Merchants and technicians.
- Ordered new terminals to replace broken ones, as well as confirmed the status of orders
- Increased transaction limits to facilitate processing of debit transactions on specific terminals.
- Assisted customers in reversing incorrect transactions done on POS terminals.

Education

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Experienced in multitasking with solid knowledge of research and customer relations.
- Solid knowledge of inventory management.
- Very fluent in French and English (speaking and writing).
- Good at adapting to new environment thus facilitating a smooth transition in my job.
- proficiency: MS Word, Office, PowerPoint, and some basic software program (IOS AND WINDOWS) maintenance.
- Ongoing studies as a oracle SQL developer.